solidworks.com 2014-12-16

# Privacy Policy | SOLIDWORKS

**Dassault Systèmes SolidWorks Corporation Privacy Policy**

Dassault Systèmes SolidWorks Corporation (DS SolidWorks) would like to thank you for visiting our website. We know many visitors have questions regarding the privacy of their interactions with DS SolidWorks. We hope this privacy policy statement will answer any questions you may have, but if it does not, please feel free to contact us at the email address or postal address shown below.

Please note that most SolidWorks® products are sophisticated computer-aided design software products aimed at mechanical engineers and other manufacturing and design professionals. SolidWorks products generally cost thousands of Dollars/Euros per license and DS SolidWorks does not consider them to be consumer products.

Information about DS SolidWorks' compliance with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework is available at [http://www.SolidWorks.com/sw/truste.htm](http://www.solidworks.com/sw/truste.htm).

**Information Collected from Online Visitors**

In general, you can visit the DS SolidWorks website without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself, such as your name, phone number, or postal or email address. Our web server collects IP addresses to obtain certain aggregate information concerning the use of our website. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you’re surfing the web. We do not link IP addresses to any personally identifiable information. Therefore you can remain anonymous when you visit our website.

Our web servers also collect information such as number of visits, average time spent on the site, and pages viewed; however, this information is not traceable back to an individual user. DS SolidWorks uses this information to analyze how people use our site and generate ideas on how the site might be improved.

Some of our web pages utilize "cookies" so that we can better serve you with tailored information when you return to our site. A cookie is data that our website may send to your browser and it is kept on your computer to facilitate your next visit to our site. The cookie data may improve form interactions based on information you have previously given to us. For example, in some cases, we will allow you to bypass a web form if a form cookie exists, or we may prefill a form with previously supplied contact information. You can, if you wish, set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it.

Occasionally you may be asked to give us more specific information about yourself, such as when you download software, register for a seminar or other event, respond to a survey, enter a contest from our website, and register at the customer portal. Supplying such information to us is optional, but you may be unable to complete certain transactions without giving such information.

**Entities Collecting Personal Information**

The information provided at this site is collected by Dassault Systèmes SolidWorks Corporation, 175 Wyman Street, Waltham, MA 02451. Our telephone number is 781-810-5011.

This website contains links to websites owned and maintained by other companies. Such websites may also collect personal information and such collection of personal information will be subject to the privacy policies of the site at which personal information is collected and/or the company collecting the personal information. DS SolidWorks is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any non-SolidWorks website. Please review the privacy policy of such other sites before providing them with your personal information.

**Information Collected via Marketing Activities**

DS SolidWorks conducts many different marketing activities by which it may collect your personal information. For example, we collect contact information at trade shows, we rent lists of email addresses for marketing campaigns, we invite the public to download free software from our website in return for providing us contact information, we run contests for which participants may provide basic information about themselves, and we obtain addresses from publications that target the industries from which we hope to attract customers. When we rent lists of names and addresses, we rent them from entities that provide only names of individuals who have "opted in" to receive communications from companies such as DS SolidWorks and we typically do not receive the actual contact information but only the ability to send an email or mail through the postal service to the contact from a bonded mail house or have the email list vendor send an email or mail through the postal service to the contact.

**Information Collected via License Activation and/or Registration**

At the time customers register or activate their license of SolidWorks® or other software offerings of DS SolidWorks or its affiliates, DS SolidWorks may collect information such as Company name, shipping address, contact name, contact email address, telephone number, title, role, products designed, primary CAD product in use, and industry sector. DS SolidWorks requests this information because it believes it is important to understand who its customers are and how to contact them with relevant product information. In some circumstances, DS SolidWorks may be obligated to make this information available to third parties who license component technology to DS SolidWorks that is included in the product(s) being activated. If DS SolidWorks receives an inquiry from a third party licensor regarding which individual at the company has activated a given license, DS SolidWorks may be obligated to supply the contact name in response to enable the third party to understand where its software licenses are being used.

In addition, DS SolidWorks collects and manages activation data for Dassault Systèmes DraftSight® software, and uses that data and supplemental data provided by the DraftSight customer for marketing purposes (e.g., sending newsletters and offers to DraftSight customers). The DraftSight data may also be shared with Dassault Systèmes and its other affiliates for marketing purposes.

**The Use of Personal Information**

DS SolidWorks may use the personal information you provide us for a variety of purposes, including registration, authentication, and marketing. We may use the information to inform you of special offers, contests, upgrades, and other software products and services that may be of interest to you. When you are a customer of SolidWorks, we may use your personal information to contact you for a wide array of customer relation/customer service purposes, such as to inquire whether you intend to renew subscription service agreements with DS SolidWorks or to request that you respond to a survey concerning our products and services or to address a question regarding an order.

Since SolidWorks resellers are our primary sales channel and provide the first line of support to our customers, we share personal contact information with the reseller assigned to a particular customer or in the territory of a prospect.

DS SolidWorks may also share personal information with its parent company, Dassault Systèmes, and their and our affiliates for sales and marketing purposes. Additionally, we may share personal information with business partners when the business partner is sponsoring an event with us or participating in a marketing promotion with us.

We may also provide you with materials concerning the products and/or services of our affiliates and third parties we think may be of interest to you. We may do this by emailing information to you or providing your name and address to a bonded mail house that mails information on behalf of a third party. The bonded mail house is prohibited from providing the third party with your name and contact information and is obligated to either return the information to us or destroy the list following the mailing. Unless we inform you otherwise at the point at which we collect your information, we will not provide your personal contact information directly to a third party not otherwise described herein.

DS SolidWorks products and services are not marketed to children under the age of 13 and DS SolidWorks does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. DS SolidWorks is committed to protecting the privacy of children and if DS SolidWorks becomes aware that such information was collected, it will treat that information as sensitive.

If you do not wish to receive further communications and information from DS SolidWorks, please let us know by emailing [privacy@SolidWorks.com](mailto:privacy@SolidWorks.com) and we will respect your wishes. We also contain instructions as to how you can opt-out of future email communications in the communications we send to you. If you have responded to a communication directly to a third party, you may also need to opt-out of the third party email list.

DS SolidWorks stores the personal data of website visitors and customers indefinitely and may maintain and process such information directly or indirectly in one or more databases in the United States and elsewhere. We may hire other companies to provide services on our behalf that may involve the storage and use of your personal information, such as for delivering email communications. Any such company or third party is required to maintain the confidentiality of that information and is prohibited from using that information for any purpose other than as authorized by us. If you provide personal information to DS SolidWorks, you agree and consent to the storage and usage of this information anywhere that DS SolidWorks and its affiliates maintain offices (around the world), for a variety of purposes, including those described above.

DS SolidWorks may also disclose such personal information if required by law or if DS SolidWorks believes in good faith that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (for example, a warrant, a subpoena, or other court order) or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of DS SolidWorks, our customers or the public.

**Web Site Analysis**

DS SolidWorks uses the services of a third party vendor to help us measure and analyze the effectiveness of our website and how visitors use [www.SolidWorks.com](http://www.solidworks.com/). To do this, we may use web beacons and cookies provided by this third party vendor. The type of information we collect includes the pages visited and navigation patterns, which helps us learn how visitors use our site, and what information is of the most interest to our customers and visitors to our website. Although the third party vendor logs the information coming from our site on our behalf, DS SolidWorks controls how that data may and may not be used. If you do not want to assist DS SolidWorks in improving our website, products, services, offers, and marketing strategy, you can "opt-out" of this web-site analysis tool by changing your communication preferences at <http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/policy#optout>.

**3D ContentCentral® and Other Services Requiring Registration**

DS SolidWorks hosts a 3D catalog at <http://www.3dcontentcentral.com/>. From this website, public users can find 3D models of products distributed by manufacturers and individuals identified at the site. 3D ContentCentral has its own privacy policy (see [www.3dcontentcentral.com/](http://www.3dcontentcentral.com/)). In general, a user can freely view the models, but must register with 3D ContentCentral to download the models. DS SolidWorks may pass the information it collects upon registration, which may include personal information, to the manufacturers and individuals whose models the 3D ContrentCentral user accesses and/or downloads. This requirement to share information regarding the users who access the various manufacturers’ models may be a requirement of an agreement under which a manufacturer makes its models available to 3D ContentCentral. From time to time DS SolidWorks may create other services requiring registration that may operate under similar policies.

**Updating Personal Information and "Opting Out"**

DS SolidWorks wants to ensure that the information it collects is accurate. You may notify us of any change to your address, phone number, email address or other information by sending us an email message at [privacy@SolidWorks.com](mailto:privacy@SolidWorks.com) or by notifying us in writing at:

Dassault Systèmes SolidWorks Corporation  
175 Wyman Street  
Waltham, Massachusetts 02451 U.S.A.

Attn: Legal Department

You may set or change your communication preferences by visiting [http://www.SolidWorks.com/preferences](http://www.solidworks.com/preferences).  
If at any time you wish to "opt out" of receiving information from DS SolidWorks, please notify us by sending us an email or written message to the addresses shown above or by emailing us at [privacy@SolidWorks.com](mailto:privacy@SolidWorks.com). Please note that due to lead times on certain mailings and other contacts, you may continue to receive communications for a period following your "opt out" notification. We will, however, respond to your request within 30 days.

We reserve the right to retain your information if your account is active or as might be needed for business relation and customer service purposes or to provide services to you. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Changes to this Policy**

DS SolidWorks may change this policy from time to time to reflect changes to our information practices. Any material change will be posted to this website prior to the change becoming effective. A prominent notice or flag on the website where the privacy policy is displayed will indicate the change and the date the changes becomes effective. We encourage you to review our privacy policy from time to time for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Certified SolidWorks Professional Directory and Other Public Lists; Website Community Sections**

Many SolidWorks users gain valuable professional and commercial exposure by being included in lists on the DS SolidWorks or a third-party website that identify individuals who have obtained SolidWorks Certifications or who have other recognized credentials or skills. DS SolidWorks makes this information available publicly to users of its website as a service to the individual, directly or indirectly through a third party vendor. If you are eligible to be included in such a list but do not wish your personal information to be included, please contact DS SolidWorks at the above address or via email at  [privacy@SolidWorks.com](mailto:privacy@SolidWorks.com).

DS SolidWorks provides various community activities to its users, including discussion forums (see the Support and Community pages at the SolidWorks website). Participation in these activities is voluntary and it is very likely that personal information will be exposed to other members of the community if you participate. DS SolidWorks takes no responsibility for maintaining the privacy of any personal information you make available to members of any community identified as such on the website.

Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the Share button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the features.

Our web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@SolidWorks.com](mailto:privacy@SolidWorks.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Purchasing Items or Services from the DS SolidWorks Site**

If you wish to purchase items (including software, books, or branded marketing merchandise) or services (e.g., certification training) from the site, we require your personal information such as your full name, billing address, telephone number, email address, and credit card number/expiration date. Collection and processing of information related to this purchase activity may be conducted by a third party fulfillment house that is obligated to maintain the confidentiality of the information. In certain circumstances, a third party is acting as a reseller of the items and is independently responsible for protecting your information. Please read carefully such vendors' Privacy Policies before providing your personal data. DS SolidWorks may access personal information collected by the third party vendor in order to better understand the products of interest to its customers. DS SolidWorks may use this information to notify you of other products or services it believes may be of interest to you.

DS SolidWorks works to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. We may also store information regarding your purchase (information as to what you ordered, whether and when it was fulfilled, and your contact information, not credit card information) in order to answer questions and resolve issues that may arise later.

At the time the order is placed we ask you to "opt in" so we may contact you regarding such things as sales and special offers. If you opt in we may also share your information with our affiliates, and other companies and organizations whose products we think may be of interest to you so that they may contact you. If you do not opt in we will not contact you regarding other offers or share your information unless you have given us your personal information pursuant to other DS SolidWorks marketing activities.

**Information Collected in Connection with Technical Support and Use of that Information**

Generally, DS SolidWorks’ technical support team can obtain customer contact information via the serial number and registration data it maintains in its customer database. DS SolidWorks may use this contact information to respond to support inquiries and/or to request additional information from the customer.

Occasionally DS SolidWorks must obtain files and/or model information to assist it in diagnosing technical support issues. DS SolidWorks may share model and file information provided by a customer with a licensor of component technology included in a SolidWorks product if DS SolidWorks considers that appropriate to assist it in diagnosing or resolving a customer problem. All such licensors are also contractually obligated to protect the confidentiality of customer models and files.

Some third party software that interoperates with the SolidWorks software, such as Microsoft’s Windows® operating system software, may request data from your system in order to assist in diagnosing issues. You will be informed of the need for this information and may choose whether to provide it to the third party software. The third party will be responsible for any privacy issues related to the information you provide to its software.

DS SolidWorks also maintains many of the customer files in a database it uses to conduct regression tests and other tests of later releases of the SolidWorks software.

**DS  SolidWorks Remote Support Functionality**

For customers with difficult-to-diagnose issues, DS SolidWorks has added a remote support functionality that enables DS SolidWorks to view a customer computer remotely via the Internet in real-time. This functionality is used only when authorized by the customer and while the customer is at the computer unless the customer authorizes longer durations of remote access while he or she is not at the computer. The functionality enhances the customer’s ability to explain and demonstrate the problem being experienced.

For remote support, the customer initiates a secure connection with a DS SolidWorks support engineer, enabling the support engineer to either view or take control of the customer’s system. In order to create this connection, the customer will download a small client (460KB) to his or her system that will communicate with the support engineer’s computer. This connection will be encrypted via a 168-bit secured socket layer to ensure that no data transmitted between the customer system and the SolidWorks support engineer is compromised.

The customer retains full control of his or her system throughout the session. If at any time during this session the customer wishes to terminate the remote connection, he or she may do so and upon termination the client will be completely removed from the customer’s system, and the SolidWorks support engineer will no longer be able to view or access the customer’s system.

DS SolidWorks treats all information it receives during a remote support session as confidential and proprietary customer information received for technical support purposes.

**Performance Feedback Email Tool**

DS SolidWorks products and the DraftSight software may include a feedback tool that, if turned on, sends reliability and usage information to DS SolidWorks via email or a direct HTTP network connection. The feedback tool is turned off unless turned on by the user and it may be turned off and on repeatedly at the option of the user. This data is used for quality and product improvement purposes and helps give DS SolidWorks an idea of the relative value of various functionalities within its products. The data is also used, in part, to create the reports for the CAD Admin Dashboard. The data does not include any user model data or any information that could be used to re-create models, and is reviewed by DS SolidWorks in the aggregate.

**TRUSTe Privacy Seal**

DS SolidWorks has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and privacy practices have been reviewed and certified as described below by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's program requirements available at:  
<http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html>  
including transparency, accountability, and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. As of the date of this privacy policy, the TRUSTe program certifies only information that is collected through the website [www.SolidWorks.com](http://www.solidworks.com/), and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications, social networking applications, and downloadable software. DS SolidWorks may have or may otherwise certify compliance with applicable regulatory frameworks regarding collection, use and retention of this information Additional information regarding this certification is available at [http://www.SolidWorks.com/truste](http://www.solidworks.com/truste).

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@SolidWorks.com](mailto:privacy@SolidWorks.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe at <http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint>.

**Questions or Concerns**

We hope this policy statement helps you understand DS SolidWorks practices with respect to your personal and business information. If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us at Dassault Systèmes SolidWorks Corporation, 175 Wyman Street, Waltham, Massachusetts 02451 U.S.A., Attn: Legal Department or via email at [privacy@SolidWorks.com](mailto:privacy@SolidWorks.com).

Rev.  November 14, 2014

  * Print
  * Email
